Mahmoud Zaky Fetoh

Phone: +201022381474 github.com/zaky-fetoh

Email: zaky.fetoh@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-zaky-fetoh

Objective

I am a software Engineer passionate about solving a real-world problem, working and collaborate with a great Engineers that I can learn from. I have mixed experience across various discipline such as full stack development, data Science, computer vision and mainly devops Engineer.

Education

2021 - 2023 | Faculty of Computers and Information, Menoufia university, Egypt.

M.Sc., doing computer vision research using deep learning, Graduated 2023

2015 - 2019 | Faculty of Computers and Information, Menoufia university, Egypt.

B.Sc. Honors, I graduated with the Top, 1st, Grade on my class, Excellent with honor GPA 3.5.

Professional Certificates.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate [Link] AWS Certified Machine Learning - Specialty [Link]

Work Experience

Dec 2023 - Present | ML Cloud Consultant @ Bexprt, KSA.

Involved at architecting and implementing MLOps and DevOps projects for MENA $\,$

 $\begin{array}{l} {\rm customers.} \\ {\it -Technologies:} \end{array}$

IaC: Terraform.

Clould Provider: AWS, Cloudflare.

CI/CD: Github Actions, Atlantis, Terraform Cloud.

ETL: AWS Glue Crawler, Glue Database, Glue Job, S3, Firehose.

MLOps: SageMaker, bentoml, Prefect, MLflow, DVC.

Micro-frontend: Cloudfront, S3, Route53.

Monitoring: DataDog, NewRelic. Container Orchestrators: ECS.

May 2023 - Dec 2023 | **DevOps Engineer** @ **n-go**, KSA.

Administrating kubernetes clusters for 1M user Application.

- Technologies:

Clould Provider: AWS, OCI, Cloudflare. Container Orchestrators: EKS, OKE. CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub actions, ArgoCD.

kubernetes Autoscaler: Cluster Autoscaler, karpenter. Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, ELK, Kiali, Jaeger.

IaC: Terraform, Kustomize, Helm, Ansible.

VPN & ZTN: Pritunl, Twingate.

Service Mesh: Istio.

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023 | MLops Engineer @ Susoft, Norway.

Building microservice application for Training and deploying machine and deep learning models for Sales forecasting. Performing customer segmentation to direct marketing campaigns.

 $\hbox{\it -} Technologies:$

Model Training: PyTorchForecasting, Pytorch, pandas, Prophet, NeuralProphet.

Model Monitoring: Weight and biases, Prometheus, Grafana.

Model Serving: torchScript, Docker, K8s.

Model Registry: Minio.

Asynchronous communication for issuing train request is done using RabbitMQ

Gateway and load balancing services performed using NodeJS.

[Page 1 of 3]

Teaching & Research Assistant @ Menoufiya University, Egypt.

Teaching machine Learning and Computer vision Courses.

Frameworks & Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, NodeJS, GoLang (learning)

HTTP Servers Frameworks: ExpressJS, Flask.

Version Control Tools: Git, Github, Bitbucket.

Data Science: PyTorch, Pandas, statsmodels, Prophet, Numpy, OpenCV, Plotly,

LLAMA 2, PaddleOCR.

MLOps: SageMaker, Prefect, bentoml, Mlflow, Hydra, DVC.

Client API: REST, GraphQL, gRPC, SocketIO. Security Utilities: Joi, Jsonwebtoken (JWT), OAuth 2.0.

Databases: MONGODB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB.

Adminstration: CCNA, MCSA, RHCSA, Kubernetes,

 ${\bf Clould\ Provider};\quad {\rm AWS,\ OCI,\ Cloudflare}.$

Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, ELK, kiali, jaeger, DataDog, NewRelic.

Container Orchestrators: EKS, OKE, ECS, Docker-Compose.

Infrastucture as Code: Terraform, Kustomize, Helm, Ansible.

CI/CD: Atlantis, Terraform Cloud, Jenkins, Github Actions, ArgoCD.

VPN & ZTN: Pritunl, Twingate, Cloudflare Warp.

Message Broker: RabbitMQ, Kafka.

Documentation: Swagger, LATEX.

Caching: Redis, MinIO.

Publications

2022 Multiscale aware classification of COVID-19 from Chest X-Ray using a spatially weighted atrous spatial pyramid pooling CNN [Link].

Mahmoud Z fetoh, Khalid M. Amin, Ahmed M. Hamad

In this paper I propose, scale invariant CNN architecture for COVID-19 classification. Proposed model based on building a scale space in each layer using Atrous spatial pyramid pooling then selecting a correct space to operate at using spatial attention module.

2021 COVID-19 Detection Based on Chest X-Ray Image Classification using Tailored CNN Model, [Link]. Mahmoud Z fetoh, Khalid M. Amin, Ahmed M. Hamad

In this paper I propose a very light-weight model as a consequence of using spatial separable kernel and depth-wise separable kernels for COVID-19 classification.

Published at: IJCI.